So, let's go to probability distributions.
我们来讨论下概率分布
Let's say we have a coin,
假设有一枚硬币
and we toss it twice.
投掷两次
Let's say we get one heads and one tails.
一次是正面 一次是背面
What would we think about this coin?
这个硬币的正反面概率如何？
Well, it could be a fair coin, right?
可能比较公平
It could also be slightly biased towards either heads or tails.
也有可能稍微偏向于正面或背面
We don't have enough data to be sure.
数据不足 无法判定
So, let's say that our verdict is that we think it's fair,
假设我们认为它很公平
but with not much confidence.
但是并不是很确定
So, let's think of the probability p that this coin lands on heads.
我们思考下这枚硬币正面朝上的概率 p
With a little bit of confidence,
保持一定的置信水平的话
p is one half,
p 为 1/2
but it could be a lot of other values.
但是也可能是其他值
So, the probability distribution for p is something like this graph.
因此 p 的概率分布是这样的图形
Higher at one half,
1/2 处更高
but a bit even in the entire interval,
但是整个区间内比较均匀
and very low on the corner zero and one.
角落 0 和 1 处非常低
Now, let's say we toss the coin 20 times and we get 10 heads, 10 tails.
假设投掷硬币 20 次 10 次正面 10 次背面
Now, we have a bit more confidence that the coin is fair.
现在更有信心相信硬币很公平
So, the distribution for the new value p is something more like
新值 p 的分布更像这个图形
this graph with a higher peak at 0.5.
0.5 的峰值更高
Now, let's say we toss a coin four times,
假设投掷硬币 4 次
and we get heads three times, and tails one.
正面 3 次 背面 1 次
The probability distribution for p is now centered at
p 的概率分布现在以 0.75 为中心
0.75 since we get three heads out of four tries.
因为尝试 4 次后有 3 次是正面
But also with not much confidence.
但是置信水平不高
So, it's a graph like this.
因此是这样的图形
But if we toss it 400 times,
但是如果投掷 400 次
and it lands on heads 300,
正面朝上 300 次
then we're much more confident that the value of p is close to 0.5.
那么我们非常有信心相信 p 的值很接近 0.5
Therefore, the probability distribution for p is something like
因此 p 的概率分布是这样的
this with a huge peak at at 0.75,
在 0.75 处有个很高的峰值
and almost flat everywhere else.
其他地方都几乎是扁平的
This is called a Beta distribution,
称之为 β 分布
and it works for any values of A and B.
适合任何 a 和 b 值
If we get heads A times and tails B times,
如果正面朝上 a 次 背面朝上 b 次
the graph looks like this with a peak at A over A+B.
图形是这样的 在 a/a+b 处出现峰值
The formula is this.
公式是这样的
Gamma of A plus B,
Г(a+b)
divided by Gamma of A times Gamma of B,
除以 Г(a)Г(b)
times X to the A minus one,
乘以 x 的 a-1 次幂
times Y to the B minus one.
乘以 y 的 b-1 次幂
If you haven't seen the Gamma function,
如果你没有见过伽马函数
think of it as a continuous version of the factorial function.
可以看做阶乘函数的连续版本
In this case, if A is an integer,
在此示例中 如果 a 是整数
then Gamma of A is A minus one factorial.
则 Г(a) 是 a-1 的阶乘
For example, Gamma of five is four factorial,
例如 Г(5) 是 4 的阶乘 结果为 24
which is 24, and Gamma of six is five factorial, which is 120.
Г(6) 是 5 的阶乘 结果为 120
But the interesting thing about
关于伽马函数 比较有趣的一点是
the Gamma function is that it also takes values in between.
它还可以计算带小数点的值
So, we can define things like Gamma of 5.5,
例如可以计算 Г(5.5)
and it will be something between 24 and 120.
结果将在 24 和 120 之间
The actual formula for the Gamma function is in
讲师备注中介绍了伽马函数的实际公式
the instructor comments although is not something we'll use in this class.
但是在这节课我们不会用到
So, what happens if we have values that are not integers like say,
如果值不是整数 会怎样
0.1 for heads, and 0.4 for tails.
例如正面为 0.1 背面为 0.4
This makes no sense since we can get 0.1 heads and 0.4 tails.
这是不合理的 因为不可能有 0.1 次正面 0.4 次背面
But that's okay for the Beta distribution.
但是对于 β 分布来说是可以的
We just need to grab the right formula using the Gamma function.
我们只需使用伽马函数绘制正确的公式
For values smaller than one,
对于小于 1 的值
like 0.1 and 0.4,
例如 0.1 和 0.4
we get this graph.
得出这个图形
That means p is much more likely to be either close
表明 p 更有可能接近 0 或 1
to zero or close to one than to be in the middle.
而不是中间值
This makes a bit of sense, right?
比较合理 对吧
If p is closer to zero or to one,
如果 p 接近 0 或 1
then we're likely to have either zero heads or zero tails,
则表明要么是 0 次正面 要么是 0 次背面
which at least gets us close to one of the values 0.1 or 0.4.
至少让我们接近值 0.1 或 0.4 之一